Okay, so you've had your first attempt at writing code and fixing errors.
좋습니다. 이제 당신은 첫번째 코드작성 및 오류 수정을 배우셨습니다.
This type of experimentation is a critical part of learning
이번 실험은 이번 배움에서 중요한
Android development.
Android 개발입니다.
Let's talk about the size of views now.
이제 관점에 대해서 이야기해볼텐데요.
We know that the width and height are expressed in DP values, or
저희는 넓고 높게 DP 값을 표현하거나
density independent pixels.
집중적으로 독립 픽셀을 표시했습니다.
This makes it look good across a range of different devices.
이 과정은 다른 장치에서 보기 좋게 만들어 줍니다.
However, there's still room for improvement in this UI.
그러나 이 UI에서 발전할 수 있는 공간이 있습니다.
If I change this text here to be something longer, for example wait,
이 텍스트를 조금 더 긴 것으로 바꾼다면
today's your birthday?
오늘이 생일인가요?
Notice the text updates here, but it wraps to two lines.
여기 텍스트가 확인되지만 두줄로 표시되네요.
Ideally it would all be on one line,
한줄에 표시되면 좋겠죠.
because there is plenty of screen real estate on this side.
왜냐하면, 화면 다른 쪽에 공간이 남기 때문이죠.
The reason the box didn't change sides,
박스는 여백을 변경하지 안기에
is because we gave it a fixed width and height of 150dp.
넓이 및 높이를 150dp로 변경해야합니다.
When you set a very specific value for
값을 다음과 같이 상세히 설정할 때
width and height like this, this is called hard coding a value.
넓이와 높이를 설정하고 이는 하드 코딩 값이라고 부릅니다.
It's generally considered not a good practice,
이는 보편적으로 고려되며 좋은 연습은 아닙니다,
because if the text ever changes like this, then it looks funny.
왜냐하면 텍스트가 변경되면, 이는 우습게 보이기 때문입니다.
We have to go and change the width to something like 200, so
저희는 넓이를 변경해야합니다 아마 200정도, 그리고
that it fits all on one line.
이는 한줄에 모두 맞춰집니다.
But it would be such a hassle to keep updating the width and
하지만 이는 너무 급박하게 넓이를 변경하며
height, based on what the text is.
높이 역시 텍스트에 맞추어 변경합니다.
You might not know what the text is until later.
하지만, 텍스트 양을 나중에 아는 경우가 있을 수 있는데요.
For example, if you have an app that's showing news articles,
예를들어, 만약 당신이 뉴스 기사를 보여주는 앱이 있다면,
the title of each story may change.
제목은 항상 변할 것입니다.
And you don't want your UI to break, if you have a really long title or
그리고 UI를 변화하고 싶지 않다면 당신은 정말 긴 제목 혹은
if you have a really short title.
정말 짧은 제목을 사용해야할지 모릅니다.
So in Android we can solve this problem by setting the width
그래서 안드로이드에서 저희는 넓이를 설정하여 문제를 해결할 수 있습니다.
to be a special value called wrap content.
특별값은 랩 양식이라고 불립니다.
This address, the width of the TextView, so
이 주소는, TextView넓이 그리고,
that it's precisely the width of the content inside of it.
컨텐츠가 포함될 넓이를 포함합니다.
It's not too short and it's not too large.
이는 너무 짧아서도 너무 커서도 안됩니다.
It's just right.
정확해야합니다.
Similarly for height instead of setting it to 150 dp, we
150 dp설정 높이 대신에 우리는
can set it to the special value of wrap content, then the text view will update,
특별한 값으로 컨텐츠를 포함할 수 있는 값을 설정하고, 텍스트 보기를 업데이트 할 수 있습니다.
so that the size of the text use only as tall as the text inside of it.
그렇다면 텍스트 사이즈는 단지 내부에서 같은 높이로 유지될 것입니다.
Now, setting wrap content for height and width is very powerful, because you
이제, 높이 및 넓이를 설정하면, 매우 강력한 양식이 됩니다. 왜냐하면,
might have content decided on the right here, which will now be shifted over,
당신은 한줄안에 양식을 알맞은 공간에 포함할 수 있게 되기 때문이며,
because you don't have this excess space in the text view.
텍스트 양식보다 큰 공간을 소비할 필요가 없습니다.
And similarly, if you have other text views below this,
그리고 유사하게, 만약 당신의 다른 텍스트가 아래에 있다면,
now they can shift up to right below this first text view.
이제 당신은 조정하여 알맞은 모습으로 만들 수 있습니다.
Back to the news app example, if this was the story title, you wouldn't
뉴스 앱으로 돌아가서, 만약 기사 제목이 있다면, 당신은
want the story description to be all the way down here, 150 DPIs away.
모든 설명을 150DPI에 표현하고 싶지 않을 것입니다.
Instead, you'd want the description to be right up under the story title.
대신, 당신은 설명을 이야기 제목 아래 표현하고 싶을 것입니다.
Zooming back out, let's try a shorter string.
사이즈를 낮춘 후, 짧은 줄을 만들어봅시다.
Okay, it's time for you to practice now.
이제, 연습할 시간입니다.
We want you to change a couple things with the code.
이 코드에서 몇가지만 수정하고자합니다.
Change the width and the height of the TextView to wrap content.
TextView에서 텍스트를 감싸고 있는 영역의 높이 및 넓이를 변경합니다.
Then change the text to be a really long, long sentence, or paragraph, so
그리고 텍스트를 정말 긴 문장 혹은 문단으로 바꾼 후
that it displays more than one line of text on the device preview.
미리보기에 한줄이 넘는양식으로 표시해보세요.
You can even type out the full birthday song if you wanted, that's pretty long.
당신은 생일 축하노래를 입력하여 원하는 줄을 만들 수 있습니다.
The code to get you started is linked below.
이와 같은 방법을 할 수 있는 코드는 아래와 같습니다.